# **ALLDREEN DEV W P**

alldreen94@gmail.com

**9677331173** 

https://www.linkedin.com/in/alldreen-dev-91680311b/

Designation: Senior Software Engineer (Embedded – Automation) at Robert Bosch Engineering and Business Solutions

Summary Coimbatore, India

Embedded Software Engineer with 4 years' experience with Embedded Systems, Python Programming and Automation. Good understanding in the Software Development Life cycle and Software Testing Life cycle in Automotive Industry. Proven abilities in demonstrating both technical and soft skills in product development with Agile Methodology.

## **Education**

**PSG** College of Technology

GPA: 8.54/10

Coimbatore, India

Bachelor of Engineering - Electronics and Communication Engineering

Aug 2012 - May 2016

# **Work Experience**

Associate Software Intern

Jan 2016 - April 2016

- OpenCV Algorithm Development to perform template matching in Infotainment Display with 98% accuracy.
- Text extraction using Tesseract-OCR to validate texts in Infotainment System Displays.
- Automated USB multiplexer switching and relay box control via serial communication to reduce the binary flashing time of V850 microcontroller by 15%.

Associate Software Engineer

July 2016 - Oct2019

### NGI project - Diagnostics Automation - V850:

- Automated 400 test cases based on UDS (Unified Diagnostics Services) using CANoe COM API's using python.
- Developed python serial interface module to send, validate and log serial data in V850 and RH850 microcontrollers.
- Automated DLT client application using DLLs to Monitor and store logs and to send DLT injection to DLT daemon running in the Target.

### Premium Convergence - QC 820am:

- Automated flashing mechanism via fast boot in Qualcomm 820am to aid continuous flashing job from Jenkins.
- Integrated SSH library to communicate with SSH daemon in Hypervisor environment (QNX hypervisor, QNX host, Android guest domain in Qualcomm 820am processor) for command execution and application deployment.
- Automated logging, screen capture, shell command execution of Android domain in QC 820am using Android Debug Bridge (ADB) and Python.
- Android UI touch automation solution using APPIUM server to perform touch validation with 5x Speed.

Senior Software Engineer

Oct 2019 - Present

### Daimler CIVIC project - Samsung Exynos:

- Developed socket application to automate Robot Test Framework for continuous Testing using python.
- Developed libraries such as PPS, SSH, Serial, Image processing libraries in Robot Framework OSS for testing.
- Configure Jenkins job in CX pipeline for binary download from Artifactory, Flashing, Automated testing using Robot Framework and reporting via mail increasing the test efficiency of Samsung Exynos microprocessor by 30%.
- Automated RTC and JIRA for automated issue item creation using REST Api's in case of failure from CX.
- Developed a web application using Flask Web Framework to track the test execution status of test rigs. Flask restful api, SQL alchemy and request api were used for handshakes and database management.
- Automated third party vendors tools such as cleaware, GOEPEL, RDS and NI-DAQ tools for test automation.

## Courses and Certifications of https://github.com/AlldreenDev

- Machine Learning A-Z with scikit-learn library –Udemy
- German Language Certification (A2 Level) Binoculus Bosch
- AWS certified Solution Architect Associate Cloud guru

- UML Training Bosch
- Agile Methodology Bosch
- AWS Learning by coursera

#### Achievements

- CSR Volunteer Award
- Best 5s Practitioner
- Received six times Bosch ECP Department Employee Recognition Award

## **Skills**

Languages: Python (Excellent) C (Intermediate) OS: Windows, Linux (Basic – QNX and Android)

Tools: Pycharm, Spyder, Git, Oracle VM, Canoe, Clear case, EA, Jenkins, AWS Console, visual studio, vim